In this lesson, we are going to see how to configure our ADC to work in interrupt mode.
So I'm going to create a new project over here for new project.
I'll select my microcontroller.
It is the SDM.
Thirty two four one one.
You can select it at a nuclear discovery port.
Anyone is fine.
Oh, just select this.
I say no.
Over here.
And Eau Claire dippin out by coming over here.
Note Claire Penult.
And I'm going to select PSU to be my ADC for this experiment.
Close this.
Come over here quick.
This.
PSU becomes a DC one input's zero.
So we can go ahead to a clock configuration, we know what ATC is.
Can I go to the APB to us?
Um, so the board I selected, I selected a nuclear if not changed in it, then this is the frequency
it's giving me the default frequency.
Um, APB to is currently at at at 84 megahertz.
You can keep this the same or you can just change it.
I'm gonna send this to 60 mickum uh, 60 megahertz, which is fine.
If you're doing something that requires more frequency, you can certainly change it.
Um, let's see.
OK, so the reason I'm setting it like this is because some of you may have the estimate that two F
four was zero one boat and that one's default frequency 60 megahertz.
So I want us to keep within the same such that we can all try it on different versions of the F forebode.
So.
OK.
And my AP two, which is the, um, the, um, the bus for the ATC is also at 16 megahertz this fine.
I'll go to pan out in configuration and click system view over here.
And once this opens, I'll click the ADC and I'll configure the ADC.
OK.
It opened over here.
So click here to expand it.
I've come down here probably to certains and no krunk this port.
And over here, the clock pre-schooler is telling me that is dividing my clock source by two, which
is my 16 megahertz.
This has been divided by two, which you end up with eight megahertz.
This is fine.
Over here.
Keep everything the same.
And then just change the, um, come to the rank over here.
Cause we have one channel.
We have just rank one.
I'm gonna change sampling time to four eighty or we have to don't actually come to the end, fix certain
stuff.
And um, enable our ATC one global interrupt such that we'll be notified whatever, whenever a conversion
is complete.
Now we can go ahead and generate the code or click generate over here.
I'll give it a name or simply call this ADC.
Underscore.
Interrupt.
And, um, I'll select my two chain over here.
SDM 32.
And then keep everything the same and click here to generate code.
Click here to open the project.
There's a project.
It's opened close, this old one.
This is it.
ABC interrupt over here.
No, no.
Open this and clean up a bit.
Okay, we've cleaned up.
So what we have to do is start the ATC would interrupt.
I'll come down here and see how underscore.
ADC, let's call start.
On the score, 84 interrupt.
And this takes one argument.
The address of the ATC Hondo, which is ATC, each ATC one over here.
I'll pass that over here.
And then with The Ambersons sign here like this.
Right.
So this starts the ADC with interrupt.
So because we use an interrupt, we have to define our Kobuk, we need to go to our ADC module, come
to drivers over here, source.
And then you find your ADC to see fall.
And then in there, you find the Kobuk.
To find a callback, we can just search for the keyword, because we know we are often pretended.
They often start with a word weak.
So do control F and then underscore school week.
And then I hear this.
OK.
This is not a one we want.
We want confession complete.
Yeah, we go ladies.
Conversion complete callback.
So I just copy this.
And I'll come to my mind or see you fall over here and I can put us anywhere.
It's a function so it doesn't have to be within that of another function.
So I'll clean the key word here and all of this can be eliminated like this.
So so what this means is once the conversion is complete, the, um, the the program would jump to
this Kobuk function to execute one of others on ADC conversion complete whenever the conversion is complete.
We'll come to this function.
What do we want to do whenever.
An ABC conversion is complete.
If you want to run an algorithm, you can put it in this function if you want to do a particular thing.
If you want to light up an entity, anything, you can do it here.
But a more appropriate and sensible thing is to get the value that was just converted.
So what we have we have to do is see how underscore ADC get value like this.
And this takes the ADC Hondo US argument on this.
We return the ADC value.
But we have to create a global variable to hold it.
You in to underscore to call this sense of value like this and sense of value here.
Oh just copy this and sense of value here.
You cause this over here like this.
Right.
Note that over here we have the um.
We have the option to use.
We can use it.
This local handle here.
Oh well.
Global undo ADC one.
Right.
One key thing because when I use in a continuous mode, when the ADC completes one conversion, it will
just run this um Kobuk and then does it will be done.
It wouldn't run any more conversions if we want to start the conversion again.
We have to call haul on the score.
ADC on this call.
Start interrupt like this.
This is key.
Without this, the ADC will just perform one conversion and it will be done like this.
Okay.
No, we are ready to build, let's click here to build and she will have.
It's built successfully.
We can run our debugger or click over here.
It's open in.
OK.
I have to reconnect my board.
So we can add our global variable here to our live expression to observe it.
I'll double click there and then concurrency to copy and I'll come to live expressions and put this
over here.
I'll remove these old ones.
They are from a previous project.
I can simply.
I can do a remove or remove all like this.
OK.
That will click.
This new one hit Enter.
And then we can, um, click to Run.
I'm gonna connect my my senseor, which is just a potential meter to P is you.
Right.
I'm going to click here to run and we can see the value here.
So there's the unlock value.
And now I've moved it to the opposite direction and this is the value we're reading.
So this ADC in interrupt mode.
Okay.